I call myself a body architect.
أُطلق على نفسي مصممة اجسام بشرية.
I trained in classical ballet
لقد تدربت على رقص الباليه التقليدي
and have a background in architecture and fashion.
ولدي خبرات في التصميم والأزياء.
As a body architect, I fascinate with the human body
وكمصممة اجسام ، فأنا مفتونةٌ بجسد الإنسان
and explore how I can transform it.
وأبحث في كيفية تغييره.
I worked at Philips Electronics
لقد عملت في شركة فيليبس للإلكترونيات
in the far-future design research lab,
في مختبر بحوث التصاميم المستقبلية ،
looking 20 years into the future.
بالنظر إلى مابعد ٢٠ سنة في المستقبل.
I explored the human skin, and how technology can transform the body.
لقد بحثت في جلد الإنسان ، وكيف أن التكنولوجيا من الممكن أن تغير شكل الجسم.
I worked on concepts like an electronic tattoo,
لقد عملت في مشاريع مثل الوشم الإلكتروني ،
which is augmented by touch,
والذي يعمل باللمس ،
or dresses that blushed and shivered with light.
أو الملابس التي تحمر خجلاً أو ترتعش بالضوء.
I started my own experiments.
وبدأت تجاربي الخاصة.
These were the low-tech approaches to the high-tech conversations I was having.
باستخدام طرق بسيطة لإيجاد حلول لكل تلك البحوث المتطورة.
These are Q-tips stuck to my roommate with wig glue.
وهذه منظفات الأذن القطنية مُلصقة بغراء بشريكي في السكن .
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
I started a collaboration with a friend of mine, Bart Hess --
بدأت بالتعاون مع زميلٍ لي ، بارت هيس --
he doesn't normally look like this --
إنه لايبدو هكذا في العادة --
and we used ourselves as models.
استخدمنا أجسادنا كنماذج.
We transformed our apartments into our laboratories,
وحوّلنا شقتنا إلى مختبراتنا ،
and worked in a very spontaneous and immediate way.
وعملنا بطريقةٍ عفويةٍ وتلقائية.
We were creating
كنا نأخذ لقطات
visual imagery provoking human evolution.
لصور تتحدى التطور البشري.
Whilst I was at Philips, we discussed this idea of a maybe technology,
وعندما كنت في شركة فيليبس ، كنا نتناقش حول فكرة وجود تقنية ،
something that wasn't either switched on or off, but in between.
لا تعمل بطريقة التشغيل أو التعطيل فقط ، ولكن فيما بينهما أيضاً.
A maybe that could take the form of a gas or a liquid.
من المحتمل أن تكون على شكل غازٍ أو سائل.
And I became obsessed with this idea of blurring the perimeter of the body,
وأصبحت مفتونةً بفكرة الضبابية حول حدود الجسم.
so you couldn't see where the skin ended and the near environment started.
بحيث لاتستطيع التمييز بين نهاية الجلد وبداية المحيط الخارجي.
I set up my studio in the red-light district
أسست معمل تصويري في منطقة الـ الرد-لايت
and obsessively wrapped myself in plumbing tubing,
وغلّفت نفسي بشكلٍ جنوني بأنابيب مياه ،
and found a way to redefine the skin
ووجدت طريقةً لإعادة تعريف الجلد
and create this dynamic textile.
وصنع ذلك النسيج الديناميكي.
I was introduced to Robyn, the Swedish pop star,
وتعرفت إلى روبن ، مغنية البوب السويدية ،
and she was also exploring
وهي أيضاً كانت تبحث
how technology coexists with raw human emotion.
عن كيفية ربط التكنولوجيا مع المشاعر الإنسانية المجردة.
And she talked about how technology with these new feathers,
وتحدثت عن كيفية ربط التكنولوجيا بهذه الكسوة ،
this new face paint, this punk, the way that we identify with the world,
هذا الوجه الجديد الملون ، هذا التجرد ، بالطريقة التي نتعرف بها إلى عالمنا ،
and we made this music video.
ومن ثم أنتجنا ذلك المشهد الغنائي.
I'm fascinated with the idea
إنني مفتونةٌ بفكرة
of what happens when you merge biology with technology,
ما ينتج من مزج علم التقنية بعلم الأحياء ،
and I remember reading about this idea of being able to reprogram
وأتذكر بأنني قرأت عن طريقةٍ لإعادة برمجة
biology, in the future, away from disease and aging.
الجينات ، في المستقبل ، لتفادي الأمراض والشيخوخة.
And I thought about this concept of,
وفكرت في هذا المبدأ ،
imagine if we could reprogram
تخيلوا لو أننا تمكنا من إعادة برمجة
our own body odor, modify and biologically enhance it,
رائحة أجسادنا ، نعدلها ، ونغيرها عن طريق علم الأحياء ،
and how would that change the way that we communicate with each other?
وكيف أن ذلك سيغير من الطريقة التي نتواصل بها ؟
Or the way that we attract sexual partners?
أو الطريقة التي نجذب بها شركائنا الجنسيين؟
And would we revert back to being more like animals,
وهل سنعود لنكون أكثر شبهاً بالحيوانات ،
more primal modes of communication?
طرق أكثر بدائيةٍ للتواصل ؟
I worked with a synthetic biologist,
لذا عملت مع عالم أحياءٍ في الأعضاء الإصطناعية ،
and I created a swallowable perfume,
وأنتجت عطراً يمكن بلعه ،
which is a cosmetic pill that you eat
وهو مستحضرٌ دوائي يمكنك أكله
and the fragrance comes out through the skin's surface when you perspire.
وتخرج رائحةً عطرة من جلدك عندما تتعرق.
It completely blows apart the way that perfume is,
إنها تدمر كلياً طريقة عمل العطور ،
and provides a whole new format.
وتقدم شكلاً جديداً كلياً.
It's perfume coming from the inside out.
ورائحته تنفذ من الداخل إلى الخارج.
It redefines the role of skin, and our bodies become an atomizer.
إنها تعيد تعريف عمل الجلد ، وأجسامنا تصبح رذاذات.
I've learned that there's no boundaries,
تعلمت أنه ليس هناك حدود.
and if I look at the evolution of my work
وعندما أنظر إلى مراحل تطور عملي
i can see threads and connections that make sense.
أستطيع أن أرى مواضيع و علاقات منطقية.
But when I look towards the future,
ولكن عندما أنظر إلى المستقبل ،
the next project is completely unknown and wide open.
فإن المشروع القادم دائماً ما يكون مبهماً ، والخيارات متعددة.
I feel like I have all these ideas existing embedded inside of me,
أشعر بأن كل تلك الأفكار موجودةٌ بداخلي ،
and it's these conversations and these experiences
وأن تلك المناقشات وتلك التجارب هي التي
that connect these ideas, and they kind of instinctively come out.
تجمع تلك الأفكار مع بعضها ، فتظهر بصورةٍ تلقائية.
As a body architect,
وكمصممة اجسام بشرية ،
I've created this limitless and boundless platform
بنيت منصة غير منتهية و ليس لها حدود
for me to discover whatever I want.
لنفسي لأكتشف ما أريده.
And I feel like I've just got started.
وأشعر بأنني بدأت للتو.
So here's to another day at the office.
لذا هذا يومٌ من أيام العمل في المكتب.
(Laughter) (Applause)
(ضحك) (تصفيق)
Thank you!
شكراً لكم!